RESUME



EDUCATION

JUN 2002 - APR 2006

B.E Computer Science

Anna University, Chennai

SKILLS

Software:

- Python
- Machine Learning
- NLP
- Power builder
- Web scraping
- R language
- Advance Excel
- Tableau
- Qlik Sense

Database

- My SQL
- Sybase

Version Control

▲ Ci+Uuh

Address: plot no.134, 6th street, Maruthi nagar, Madambakkam,, Chennai – 600126

RAJESH J

Data Analyst

Phone: +91 9345186903, |Email:rajesh112j@gmail.com

Git Hub: https://github.com/rajesh-gihub

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rajesh-j-87b77221a/

ABOUT ME

I am I2 years experienced software professional, budding Data Scientist. To explore new areas and work in data science career, work for an organization which provides me to improve my skills and knowledge to grow along with organization objective Looking forward to analyze data in any domain

WORK EXPERIENCE

April 2021 - Oct 2021

FlipRobo Technologies | India

- Around 30+ projects worked in data science.
- Data cleansing, data visualization with graph, model building and data prediction.
- Trained in Python, Statistics, Machine learning and Web scraping
- Predictions based on given data of different formats and from Web based portals like Flipkart, Amazon etc.
- Analyzing the data from web pages by Web Scraping, implementing in Python, R studio software, R-shiny,
- Handling those data with Reporting Tools like Tableau, Advanced Excel

MAR 2015 - FEB 2020

IT programmer | Volume Cocomo Apparels Inc | Cambodia

Power builder developer in ERP product used in garments industry. Compiled and maintained important records such as garment packing requirements, carton specification, packing

JUN 2008 - JAN 2015

Software Programmer | India

ECO Tech PVT LTD, Chennai - India

Configured, installed and handled troubleshooting tasks for variety of different modules in application. Ensured implementation is tailored to client needs by focusing solutions on industry-specific workflow, client base and protocols

Key Projects in Data Science

1. HR-Employee-Attrition

Tech stack: Python, Machine learning, jupyter notebook **Objective**: Building a model based on Employee Atrrition.

Solution: Did EDA, treated null values, removed outliers, did hyper-parameter

tuning, built 5-6 models based on different parameters

Achievements: SVC having a f1 score of 93 and cross validation score of 89,

hyper-parameter tuning of 99.21 and AUC score of 100%

2. Census Income Prediction:

Tech stack: Python, Machine learning, jupyter notebook

Objective: The prediction task is to determine whether a person makes over \$50K a year

Solution: Did EDA, treated null values, removed special characters, skewness removal, Balancing of the imbalance target variable and standardization, did hyper-parameter tuning for some of best models, built 5-6 models based on different parameters

Achievements: **RandomForestClassifier** having a f1 score of 94 and cross validation score of 94, hyper-parameter tuning of 94.1 and AUC score of 99%